<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-08T09:27:06+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/</id><title type="html">Read Write Speak Thai - Free App to learn Thai</title><subtitle>Read write speak thai, mobile application on iOS and Android to learn to read Thai. Color the tone, read sentences and words. 
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Futur of Read Write Speak Thai</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/futur-of-readwritespeakthai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Futur of Read Write Speak Thai" /><published>2018-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/futur-of-readwritespeakthai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/futur-of-readwritespeakthai/">&lt;p&gt;Hi Thai learner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today in preview, the next development revealed for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;daily-sentences&quot;&gt;Daily Sentences&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new mode for the sentences part of the application which will help your learning process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The super algorithm behind the scene is going to propose you a number of sentences to review each day to become a fluent Thai speakers (or at least better than before ^^).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to review everyday to unlock the prestigious 30 days in a row and discover the surprise behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;achievements&quot;&gt;Achievements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the perfect time to introduce the achievement system!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small gamification of the app to add some fun during your time in the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collect all the achievements to become a rock super star of Thai, and redeem some exclusive title and joy that you can share with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got many reviews that the application is a bit too hard for beginner… and so that’s why I’m going to focus more on them on the next releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’m going to add for beginner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new mode to learn the consonant / vowel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quizz for consonant / vowel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For intermediate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat with May (A super intelligent bot ^^)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow us on the social media to know when the release will be out!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hi Thai learner!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Read Write Speak Thai in Latitudes Magazine</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/published-in-latitudes-magazine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Read Write Speak Thai in Latitudes Magazine" /><published>2018-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/published-in-latitudes-magazine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/published-in-latitudes-magazine/">&lt;p&gt;A really cool French/English magazine called &lt;a href=&quot;http://magazinelatitudes.com&quot;&gt;Latitudes&lt;/a&gt; have made a nice article
about Read Write Speak Thai.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A really cool French/English magazine called Latitudes have made a nice article about Read Write Speak Thai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why is it important to be able to read Thai?</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/first-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why is it important to be able to read Thai?" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/first-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/first-blog/">&lt;p&gt;When you are learning languages, it is important to build a good foundation. A house without correct foundation will be destroyed when the wind come. Use that image to represent your motivation and your knowledge of the Thai language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning Thai without learning how to read the symbols of the language is a mistake because you’ll be limited a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are missing a lot of ressources (Books, Magazines, Newspapers) which let you learn a lot of new vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot read the sign in the street.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot read the menu from restaurant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;read-from-newspaper--books&quot;&gt;Read from newspaper / books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;newspapers&quot;&gt;Newspapers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading the newspaper will help you a lot in getting some new vocabulary (at least the most used one). It will give you more insight of the life of your city or neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bangkok Post have a really good website which guide you to the learning process by giving you some translations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.bangkokpost.com/search/result?category=news&amp;amp;q=learning+Thai&quot;&gt;website here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of book should you read ? What you like obviously ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why not taking a book about a new skill that you want to get?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or a skill you have already and you want to improve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sign-in-the-street&quot;&gt;Sign in the street&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signalisation is quite ok, because they are international and sometimes translated in english.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all the other sign like promotions, entrance, name of a university or building are not always translated. It’s quite frustrating to do not know what the building you are looking at is !!! Especially when they look really nice ^^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;menu-from-the-restaurant&quot;&gt;Menu from the restaurant&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe me… you miss a lot of the Thai food when you don’t know how to read Thai. Thankfully, they have a lot of menu with pictures but still … it’s not the full menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading is quite important to make a good foundation of the Thai language and it’s quite useful in many situation. If you decide to skip it and learn the language with the English transliteration or IPA, go for it but you’ll miss a lot of ressources.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When you are learning languages, it is important to build a good foundation. A house without correct foundation will be destroyed when the wind come. Use that image to represent your motivation and your knowledge of the Thai language.</summary></entry></feed>