<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-07T03:34:08+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Read Write Speak Thai - Free App to learn Thai</title><subtitle>Read write speak thai, mobile application on iOS and Android to learn to read Thai. Color the tone, read sentences and words.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">V7 is available</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/v7-is-available" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="V7 is available" /><published>2018-11-06T04:40:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-06T04:40:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/v7-is-available</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/v7-is-available">&lt;p&gt;Today, I released the version 7 of Read Write Speak Thai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a description of what is new inside the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;remove-the-related-sentences-in-words&quot;&gt;Remove the related sentences in Words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes … I removed it! As the database grow, that feature was slowing down the whole thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s coming back soon, I just need to adapt some of the code to make it more performant and so your app won’t be buggy or laggy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;adding-the-flag-for-english-translation&quot;&gt;Adding the flag for english translation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on top of the carousel, you can see a new flag (US one) which when you click will hide or display the english translations of what you are reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something asked a lot lately so here it is … ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, I show the english translation, but soon I’ll switch to no english translations first, and you’ll have to click to see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW: I’m working on something to let you &lt;strong&gt;choose the flag&lt;/strong&gt; ^^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-section---dont-know-how-to-read-yet&quot;&gt;New section - Don’t know how to read yet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is not meant to learn how to read, but more as a tool/ ressource to help you in your learning trip ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why, I now link to resources which are meant to learn how to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1st - &lt;a href=&quot;http://learnthaionline.com/amember/aff/go/joba&quot;&gt;Rapid way to learn Thai&lt;/a&gt; by Gary Orman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the chance to met the guy, follow his course and it’s very interesting and well done! The method that he’s teaching is very effective and will for sure result in you being able to read Thai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He also has a huge collection of resources (Audio + Video + Subtitle) of movies / video clip / Novel available which helps a lot to practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://learnthaionline.com/amember/aff/go/joba&quot;&gt;Read more about his method on his website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is an affiliate link, so the app will get a commission if you purchase anything from it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2nd is the Other resources section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sections contains YouTube channel and books that I recommend. If you get any other channel or books that you’ll recommend, feel free to contact us via the &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;android-only---improvement&quot;&gt;Android Only - Improvement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android is dropping the support for version 4.4.x (which has over 4 years now) and so we did too - Sorry for those having old version of Android :( but dropping that version will make the app more performant for more than 90% of the other users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;website-improvement&quot;&gt;Website improvement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m slowly improving this website with now a new section called App feature where you’ll be able to find all the app feature with a description to help you to use them correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of new feature are on the pipe! Stay tuned to know what’s going to be there next ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today, I released the version 7 of Read Write Speak Thai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Small conversations in app - v6.2.8</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/small-conversations-in-app" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Small conversations in app - v6.2.8" /><published>2018-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/small-conversations-in-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/small-conversations-in-app">&lt;p&gt;The goal of the app is to provide you, &lt;strong&gt;ressources&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;tools&lt;/strong&gt; to practice and improve your Thai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first started with &lt;strong&gt;colorised sentences&lt;/strong&gt; (to show the tone easily) plus a set of tools like &lt;strong&gt;Play the sentence&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Play the word&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Search in Thai or in English&lt;/strong&gt; a set of sentences, &lt;strong&gt;Copy&lt;/strong&gt; the sentences to &lt;strong&gt;paste&lt;/strong&gt; it somewhere else, &lt;strong&gt;Loop&lt;/strong&gt; over and over the sentence to shadow it, etc etc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, we added the &lt;strong&gt;Consonants&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Vowels&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Numbers&lt;/strong&gt; to quickly be able to find one of those symbols which we always forget ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Came later on the &lt;strong&gt;Text-To-Speech&lt;/strong&gt; tool to be able to loop/hear the pronunciation of your own sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit after, the &lt;strong&gt;Daily Sentences&lt;/strong&gt; which remind you to come back to practice a set of sentences^^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the last major feature added was the &lt;strong&gt;games&lt;/strong&gt; to test yourself on all those ressources ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now… &lt;strong&gt;Conversations!&lt;/strong&gt; Yet another feature/ressource which we hope will help you on your journey to master Thai language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Context&lt;/strong&gt; is very important when learning new sentences/languages, with small conversations, we have the chance to show you the context, how the words are used, and small simulation of life that you might use one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, there are 10 conversations available but we hope to grow that number for every new releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have interesting &lt;strong&gt;conversations&lt;/strong&gt; that you want to &lt;strong&gt;share&lt;/strong&gt; with everyone, please feel free to send it to us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The goal of the app is to provide you, ressources and tools to practice and improve your Thai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A new pack of sentences !</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-new-pack-of-sentences" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A new pack of sentences !" /><published>2018-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-new-pack-of-sentences</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-new-pack-of-sentences">&lt;p&gt;Good news!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is now on his version 6.2.7 with an added set of 412 sentences!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you all for your remarks, review, fix, etc it makes the app better and better everyday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a bit busy those days so it was difficult to add more features, but it’s coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Good news!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Previous lessons and many more sentences</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/new-feature-and-sentences" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Previous lessons and many more sentences" /><published>2018-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/new-feature-and-sentences</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/new-feature-and-sentences">&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;user&lt;/strong&gt; had a really good idea for a small feature which can be really useful, a way to access to your previous lesson (from the daily exercise).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is, now you can access to your old lesson also ( if you go to “&lt;strong&gt;Daily exercise&lt;/strong&gt;” then just under &lt;strong&gt;“Back home”&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;“Edit my settings”&lt;/strong&gt; you’ll see now a &lt;strong&gt;“Previous lesson”&lt;/strong&gt; section with all the lesson you have made).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, I fixed some design issues on Android mainly, and add a way to keep your screen awake in the carousel mode (That was annoying ;) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least, a new set of &lt;strong&gt;200 hundred sentences&lt;/strong&gt; !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the app have a total of &lt;strong&gt;735 sentences&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;1318&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;uniques words&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reviews, feedback, remarks, etc helps a lot to develop the app, feel free to contact us !!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A user had a really good idea for a small feature which can be really useful, a way to access to your previous lesson (from the daily exercise).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A v2 is approaching!</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/A-V2-is-approaching" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A v2 is approaching!" /><published>2018-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/A-V2-is-approaching</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/A-V2-is-approaching">&lt;p&gt;Do you know Lýdia Machová ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s a &lt;strong&gt;polyglot&lt;/strong&gt; (She speaks 9+ &lt;strong&gt;languages&lt;/strong&gt;) and &lt;strong&gt;organize&lt;/strong&gt; the Polyglot Gathering, a really cool event inviting a lot of polyglot and they share their experiences!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the talk of Lýdia is this one : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eT7dx52wIC8&quot;&gt;The Power of Setting Priorities in Language Learning&lt;/a&gt; that you can watch on YouTube for free where she delivers her “&lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt;” to &lt;strong&gt;learn language&lt;/strong&gt;. (I really recommend you to watch all those videos they are fantastic ;) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A brief summary of it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;there-are-4-pillars-in-language-learning&quot;&gt;There are 4 pillars in Language learning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fun&lt;/strong&gt; (your learning should be fun to keep you motivated)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quantity&lt;/strong&gt; (You should provide enough work to reach your goal)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequency&lt;/strong&gt; (Frequency is key … work a bit everyday to train your brain and memory)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System&lt;/strong&gt; (We will detail it later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-system-priorities&quot;&gt;The system: Priorities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She exposes a really nice system which is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a &lt;strong&gt;chunk of time&lt;/strong&gt; (say 2 or 3 months) you set &lt;strong&gt;priority&lt;/strong&gt; on 3 &lt;strong&gt;skills&lt;/strong&gt; that you are going to focus on. After the first chunk of time, you set new priorities (3 &lt;strong&gt;different&lt;/strong&gt; skills, or use all the same skills, or one same and 2 different, whatever ;) )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-skills-are-the-following-but-im-sure-we-can-find-some-others&quot;&gt;The skills are the following, but I’m sure we can find some others&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Listening&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speaking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pronunciation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grammar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as an example, for the &lt;strong&gt;first two months&lt;/strong&gt;; you select to focus on &lt;strong&gt;Listening&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;pronunciation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;vocabulary&lt;/strong&gt;. That does not mean that you are not going to do some grammar or speaking, but your &lt;strong&gt;main focus&lt;/strong&gt; is going to be on those 3 skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;set-smart-goals&quot;&gt;Set SMART goals&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to the priority, it’s important to set SMART goal (&lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;pecific - &lt;strong&gt;M&lt;/strong&gt;easurable - &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;mbitious - &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;ealistic - &lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;ime-bound).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept is quite known so I won’t develop it; there are a ton of articles written about it (ex : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smartsheet.com/blog/essential-guide-writing-smart-goals&quot;&gt;Article 1&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yourcoach.be/en/coaching-tools/smart-goal-setting.php&quot;&gt;Article 2&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ok-ok-cool--but-whats-the-correlation-with-the-app&quot;&gt;Ok ok cool … but what’s the correlation with the app?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The title ! The v2 is approaching ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I currently consider the app as a ressource to learn Thai focusing on &lt;strong&gt;reading, listening, vocabulary and speaking&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s a material which is created by the team here and proposed to you. I want to evolve to propose you all the skills seen upper and more&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;where-i-want-to-go&quot;&gt;Where I want to go?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want the app to be more a “coach-ressource-tool” application where you go everyday to practice or encode what you did or find any ressource that suit you the best for your learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want a flow like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set your &lt;strong&gt;main goal&lt;/strong&gt; (ex: Being able to read comic book in &lt;strong&gt;Thai&lt;/strong&gt; for the next year)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure your first chunk of time priorities (&lt;strong&gt;Listening - Reading - Vocabulary)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on what you’ve selected as priority, the app is going to propose you &lt;strong&gt;ressource&lt;/strong&gt; but also &lt;strong&gt;games&lt;/strong&gt; and many other &lt;strong&gt;activities&lt;/strong&gt; which will let you work on your &lt;strong&gt;priorities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each action in the app will let you earn point (&lt;strong&gt;Reading x sentences = 15 pts)&lt;/strong&gt; to measure your work - but also a “free entry” section (I speak with a Thai friend for 15 min - 50 pts)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A screen will shows you your weekly/monthly effort on learning the language as a kind of tracker, depending on the skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;when&quot;&gt;When?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this blogpost is the premise of the development … nothing has been developed yet because I’m still in the analyse phases gathering information about technical issues, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have an ETA date yet as this is a side project for me I work on it when I get time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;can-i-participate-&quot;&gt;Can I participate ?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I accept any kind of help ;) Your feedback about this blogpost is already something!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any idea which will improve the next concept, a resource that you create that you think should be in the app, feel free to contact me ^^&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Do you know Lýdia Machová ?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A new member in the team</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-new-member-in-the-team" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A new member in the team" /><published>2018-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-new-member-in-the-team</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-new-member-in-the-team">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read Write Speak Thai&lt;/strong&gt; intend to help intermediate learner to have a &lt;strong&gt;user-friendly&lt;/strong&gt; ressource to practice their &lt;strong&gt;Thai reading skill&lt;/strong&gt; through &lt;strong&gt;coloration&lt;/strong&gt; of the Thai tone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, we want you to read content which is useful to have a kind of &lt;strong&gt;WIN-WIN mode&lt;/strong&gt; where you improve your reading skill but also enrich your vocabulary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why, &lt;strong&gt;Piriya&lt;/strong&gt; is joining me in the team to write &lt;strong&gt;meaningful&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;usable&lt;/strong&gt; sentences for the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Piriya&lt;/strong&gt; is a professional translator &lt;strong&gt;English/Thai&lt;/strong&gt; which has a lot of experiences &lt;strong&gt;translating website/documents/etc.&lt;/strong&gt;.. Feel free to use the contact form if you need &lt;strong&gt;any kind of translations work&lt;/strong&gt; done by her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She already made more than a &lt;strong&gt;hundred&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;sentences&lt;/strong&gt; which have been &lt;strong&gt;published&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;today&lt;/strong&gt; in the app! Hope you are going to &lt;strong&gt;enjoy it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wait-thats-not-all&quot;&gt;Wait that’s not all…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a new step further on many new things!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, a new page on the website to add your own set of sentences into the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, I’ve got the authorization to use a really, really nice ressource from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aakanee.com/illustrations.html&quot;&gt;Aakanee&lt;/a&gt; - The illustrations for language learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll add them raw in the application (cut the border to make it mobile friendly) for you to be able to practice with your teacher/friend/language helper - and start to add some games to it. No precise plan yet, but feel free to give idea of what you want to see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Read Write Speak Thai intend to help intermediate learner to have a user-friendly ressource to practice their Thai reading skill through coloration of the Thai tone.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Start at a specific slide</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/start-at-a-specific-slide" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start at a specific slide" /><published>2018-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/start-at-a-specific-slide</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/start-at-a-specific-slide">&lt;p&gt;I’m introducing this month a new feature in the app that many people ask me and that I find also very useful !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-ability-to-start-from-a-specific-slide&quot;&gt;The ability to start from a specific slide&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now in the search (of sentences or words), you can say at which slide you want to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not the perfect solution because you won’t be able to see the sentences/words before … but technically speaking it’s the best I can propose you right now and I still think it answer to the need ;) &lt;strong&gt;(Please give me feedback about that ;) )&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As some of you might have seen, the number of words have doubled !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be able to provide the feature to add your own sentences soon (I found a very interesting algorithm to cut your sentences into words + all the words in the database, it will be very easy I hope ^^).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m introducing this month a new feature in the app that many people ask me and that I find also very useful !</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">4000 thousand words and the rise of a new mode ?</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/4000-thousand-words" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="4000 thousand words and the rise of a new mode ? " /><published>2018-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/4000-thousand-words</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/4000-thousand-words">&lt;p&gt;To prepare the mode where people can add their own sentences, I needed a huge set of words ! It will help people to enter faster the sentences without having the need to define the tone etc …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prepare the mode where people can add their own sentences, I needed a huge set of words ! It will help people to enter faster the sentences without having the need to define the tone etc …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yeah … putting the whole dictionary in the app would have take months so I’ve decided to add Chulalongkorn University’s frequency list which contains 4000 thousand words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who don’t know where is Chulalongkorn University, it’s in the heart of Bangkok (Is that info important ? not really but I was curious ^^)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/img/mapChula.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they have a really nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chula.ac.th/en/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; (I invite you to look at it ^^)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-discover-something-interesting&quot;&gt;I discover something interesting…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was doing that content input I discover something interesting which might transform in a new mode inside the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many words are composed of smaller words let’s take an example :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ออกเสียง which mean &lt;strong&gt;To pronounce&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can decompose that word like that : ออก-เสียง&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where ออก is &lt;strong&gt;To leave / Exit&lt;/strong&gt; and เสียง is &lt;strong&gt;sound.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an easy way a sound which is out ==&amp;gt; to pronounce (Logic no ? :D)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, because the application backend already have all the decomposition of words like the example that I show, I was thinking of adding a new mode where you can see those “New word composed of other words”. I find interesting to know the origin of a word, how it’s composed and it’s easier for me to remember it and probably also create new association (even if I don’t know the final word)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell me what you think about it, if it will be useful for you or I’m in a total absurd world ? :&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To prepare the mode where people can add their own sentences, I needed a huge set of words ! It will help people to enter faster the sentences without having the need to define the tone etc …</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">No sound or want to change to a male voice ? Samsung phone</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/samsung-no-sound" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No sound or want to change to a male voice ? Samsung phone" /><published>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/samsung-no-sound</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/samsung-no-sound">&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have any &lt;strong&gt;sound&lt;/strong&gt; in the app and you have a &lt;strong&gt;samsung phone&lt;/strong&gt;, follow this steps to change the Text-To-Speech from Samsung to the Google one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Samsung have made their own Text-To-Speech system but without the Thai language in it. Thankfully, all Android phone have the &lt;strong&gt;Google Text-To-Speech&lt;/strong&gt; pre-installed which have the Thai language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you want to switch from a female voice to a male voice, follow the same procedure (It will works for every &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; phone)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to your &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt; and Select &lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Screen1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Text-To-Speech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Screen2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Google Text-to-Speech(2)&lt;/strong&gt; then click on the small &lt;strong&gt;gear icon (settings - 3)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Screen3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Install voice data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Screen4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Thai&lt;/strong&gt; from the list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Screen5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose a &lt;strong&gt;voice.&lt;/strong&gt; You can take wath ever voice you want, there is male and female voice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Screen6.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Restart &lt;strong&gt;Read Write Speak Thai application&lt;/strong&gt; and click on Play from anywhere, it should work (you might have a small delay the first time).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this will help you ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or remarks, or if one steps didn’t work or is different from yours, contact us and we will help you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you don’t have any sound in the app and you have a samsung phone, follow this steps to change the Text-To-Speech from Samsung to the Google one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A small feature to rules them all</title><link href="https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-small-feature-to-rules-them-all" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A small feature to rules them all" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-small-feature-to-rules-them-all</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://readthaiapp.github.io/a-small-feature-to-rules-them-all">&lt;p&gt;If you were using the application to practice the different Thai font, it was a bit hard because to change the font you had to go in the settings each time to switch between the normal font and the hard one you were learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is why I’ve added a new button on top of the card to switch directly between the selected font and the normal font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you are like … What’s that letter !! Switch back to normal mode quickly in one click and switch it back to you hard one in another click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope it will be useful for most of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-to-help&quot;&gt;Want to help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy, let us know what you think about the app (Via the contact form, or in app there is a feature in the About section).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any kind of issue or suggestions or feature request, same same ! send us an email, post here under the blog post or what ever we listen all our channel ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put a review on the store, it help us to reach more peoples, more ideas, more motivations ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you were using the application to practice the different Thai font, it was a bit hard because to change the font you had to go in the settings each time to switch between the normal font and the hard one you were learning.</summary></entry></feed>