<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-18T09:51:04+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/</id><title type="html">Read Write Speak Thai - Free App to learn Thai</title><subtitle>Read write speak thai, mobile application on iOS and Android to learn to read Thai. Color the tone, read sentences and words. 
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A small feature to rules them all</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/a-small-feature-to-rules-them-all/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A small feature to rules them all" /><published>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/a-small-feature-to-rules-them-all</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/a-small-feature-to-rules-them-all/">&lt;p&gt;If you were using the application to practice the different Thai font, it was a bit hard because to change the font you had to go in the settings each time to switch between the normal font and the hard one you were learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is why I’ve added a new button on top of the card to switch directly between the selected font and the normal font.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when you are like … What’s that letter !! Switch back to normal mode quickly in one click and switch it back to you hard one in another click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope it will be useful for most of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-to-help&quot;&gt;Want to help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy, let us know what you think about the app (Via the contact form, or in app there is a feature in the About section).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any kind of issue or suggestions or feature request, same same ! send us an email, post here under the blog post or what ever we listen all our channel ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put a review on the store, it help us to reach more peoples, more ideas, more motivations ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you were using the application to practice the different Thai font, it was a bit hard because to change the font you had to go in the settings each time to switch between the normal font and the hard one you were learning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 new games in app to practice your Thai reading</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/7-new-games-in-app/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 new games in app to practice your Thai reading" /><published>2018-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/7-new-games-in-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/7-new-games-in-app/">&lt;p&gt;Wow Wow Wow ! It has been a crazy week of development to pop this really useful feature in the app!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to a feedback from Colin and others, we now have some small Quizz/Puzzle type of games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s quite basic right now, but useful already - more of those games will appear in the app soon ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sentences-and-words-games&quot;&gt;Sentences and words games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;find-the-correct-translations&quot;&gt;Find the correct translations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read or Listen to the sentences/word and select the correct translations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sound-what-sentenceword-is-it--english&quot;&gt;Sound: What sentence/word is it ? English&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost the same as the Find the correct translations, but here you only have the sound ;) It’s a bit harder !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sound-what-sentenceword-is-it--thai&quot;&gt;Sound: What sentence/word is it ? Thai&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Same principle as above, but with the Thai version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-tone-is-it-only-for-word&quot;&gt;What tone is it? (Only for word)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the most difficult one ;) The word is written in Thai, and you can also listen to it, and you have to find the correct tone! Take care some words have multiple tones!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;contest&quot;&gt;Contest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who will be the first one with 100 good answers ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send us a screenshot or post on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/readthaifunapp&quot;&gt;facebook page&lt;/a&gt; when you reach 100 good answers on a game ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve nothing to offer right now, but you’ll probably become a gold member if they are gold member one day ^^ so it’s still worth trying !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;want-to-help&quot;&gt;Want to help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy, let us know what you think about the app (Via the contact form, or in app there is a feature in the About section).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any kind of issue or suggestions or feature request, same same ! send us an email, post here under the blog post or what ever we listen all our channel ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put a review on the store, it help us to reach more peoples, more ideas, more motivations ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Wow Wow Wow ! It has been a crazy week of development to pop this really useful feature in the app!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A curated feed in app</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/a-curated-feed-in-app/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A curated feed in app" /><published>2018-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/a-curated-feed-in-app</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/a-curated-feed-in-app/">&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of very nice ressource made by people to teach Thai language available on Youtube, Instagram, Twitter, etc…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m quite sure that you’ve already shared one of those video to a friend… “Hey look at that video it explains super well the consonant in Thai”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-idea&quot;&gt;The idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah, that’s the main idea, no more to say ^^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m watching a lot of Youtube video, and follow instagram feed which help me in my regular basis to learn some new stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why I would like to be able to find those kind of video quite easily and fast inside the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list will be managed by me mainly, but wait wait … soon there will be an account feature, so you’ll be able to create your account and actively participate to the content of Read Write Speak Thai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I understand that some people are creating those content to promote their service (Teacher, School, etc), That’s why I’m also thinking of creating a “&lt;strong&gt;Page&lt;/strong&gt;” per &lt;strong&gt;Content Creator&lt;/strong&gt;, to promote their service inside the app. It would be interesting as a Thai learner to have access to all those information within the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when&quot;&gt;When?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my next development task after the release of the Daily Sentence mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will probably take a month to develop and test before deploying it to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-i-help-&quot;&gt;Can I help ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes ;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell me if something like that would interest you! I really need some feedback … I’m developing this application for me, but also everyone which are interested in learning Thai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes again!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give a review on the store (App store or Android Store) that is **helping A LOT.&lt;br /&gt;
**More users on the app, more is my motivation to continue that project ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes three!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have some very good video / ressource that you think should be in that curated list, feel free to send me a message (Facebook, email, form here on the site) with the address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes FOUR! (ok that’s the last one).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a content creator, and want a page on the app, please contact me, I’ll submit to you a small form to get the necessary information to create the page for you. It’s all free, no fee or else so don’t worry ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There is a lot of very nice ressource made by people to teach Thai language available on Youtube, Instagram, Twitter, etc…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Futur of Read Write Speak Thai</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/futur-of-readwritespeakthai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Futur of Read Write Speak Thai" /><published>2018-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/futur-of-readwritespeakthai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/futur-of-readwritespeakthai/">&lt;p&gt;Hi Thai learner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today in preview, the next development revealed for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;daily-sentences&quot;&gt;Daily Sentences&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new mode for the sentences part of the application which will help your learning process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The super algorithm behind the scene is going to propose you a number of sentences to review each day to become a fluent Thai speakers (or at least better than before ^^).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to review everyday to unlock the prestigious 30 days in a row and discover the surprise behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;achievements&quot;&gt;Achievements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the perfect time to introduce the achievement system!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small gamification of the app to add some fun during your time in the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collect all the achievements to become a rock super star of Thai, and redeem some exclusive title and joy that you can share with everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got many reviews that the application is a bit too hard for beginner… and so that’s why I’m going to focus more on them on the next releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’m going to add for beginner:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A new mode to learn the consonant / vowel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quizz for consonant / vowel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For intermediate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chat with May (A super intelligent bot ^^)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Follow us on the social media to know when the release will be out!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hi Thai learner!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Read Write Speak Thai in Latitudes Magazine</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/published-in-latitudes-magazine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Read Write Speak Thai in Latitudes Magazine" /><published>2018-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/published-in-latitudes-magazine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/published-in-latitudes-magazine/">&lt;p&gt;A really cool French/English magazine called &lt;a href=&quot;http://magazinelatitudes.com&quot;&gt;Latitudes&lt;/a&gt; have made a nice article
about Read Write Speak Thai.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A really cool French/English magazine called Latitudes have made a nice article about Read Write Speak Thai.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why is it important to be able to read Thai?</title><link href="https://jobijoba.github.io/first-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why is it important to be able to read Thai?" /><published>2018-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://jobijoba.github.io/first-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://jobijoba.github.io/first-blog/">&lt;p&gt;When you are learning languages, it is important to build a good foundation. A house without correct foundation will be destroyed when the wind come. Use that image to represent your motivation and your knowledge of the Thai language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning Thai without learning how to read the symbols of the language is a mistake because you’ll be limited a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You are missing a lot of ressources (Books, Magazines, Newspapers) which let you learn a lot of new vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot read the sign in the street.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You cannot read the menu from restaurant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;read-from-newspaper--books&quot;&gt;Read from newspaper / books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;newspapers&quot;&gt;Newspapers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading the newspaper will help you a lot in getting some new vocabulary (at least the most used one). It will give you more insight of the life of your city or neighbourhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bangkok Post have a really good website which guide you to the learning process by giving you some translations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the &lt;a href=&quot;https://search.bangkokpost.com/search/result?category=news&amp;amp;q=learning+Thai&quot;&gt;website here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What kind of book should you read ? What you like obviously ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But why not taking a book about a new skill that you want to get?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or a skill you have already and you want to improve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sign-in-the-street&quot;&gt;Sign in the street&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signalisation is quite ok, because they are international and sometimes translated in english.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all the other sign like promotions, entrance, name of a university or building are not always translated. It’s quite frustrating to do not know what the building you are looking at is !!! Especially when they look really nice ^^&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;menu-from-the-restaurant&quot;&gt;Menu from the restaurant&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Believe me… you miss a lot of the Thai food when you don’t know how to read Thai. Thankfully, they have a lot of menu with pictures but still … it’s not the full menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading is quite important to make a good foundation of the Thai language and it’s quite useful in many situation. If you decide to skip it and learn the language with the English transliteration or IPA, go for it but you’ll miss a lot of ressources.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When you are learning languages, it is important to build a good foundation. A house without correct foundation will be destroyed when the wind come. Use that image to represent your motivation and your knowledge of the Thai language.</summary></entry></feed>